(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
提供 まちゅまちゅ動画
Sponsored by Machumachu Douga
まちゅまちゅ動画
Machumachu Douga
夏色まつりが午後8時頃をお知らせします。
Natsuiro Matsuri is announcing that it's around 8 PM.
みんなー！こんばんわっしょーい！
Everyone! Good evening!
どうも、ホロライブの清楚担当、みんなのアイドル、夏色まつりでーす！
I am the one in charge of purity in Hololive, everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri!
ということで、今回3Dライブなので、じゃーん！
Since this is a 3D live, ta-da!
こちらを用意しました。サイリウム！
I've prepared these. Cyalumes!
みんなも勿論用意してくれてるよね？
I'm sure you all have yours ready too, right?
ということで、最後まで楽しんでいきましょう！
So, let's have fun until the very end!
では、早速1曲目聞いてください。
Now, please listen to the first song.
千本桜！
Senbonzakura!
大胆不敵にハイカラ革命
A bold and fearless Westernized revolution
磊々落々 反戦国家
Open and aboveboard, an anti-war nation
日の丸印の二輪車転がし
Rolling a bicycle with the Hinomaru mark
悪霊退散 ICBM
Evil spirits begone, ICBM
環状線を走り抜けて
Running through the beltway
東奔西走なんのその
Running east and west, thinking nothing of it
少年少女戦国無双
Boys and girls, Sengoku Musou
浮世の随に
Going along with the floating world
千本桜 夜ニ紛レ
One thousand cherry blossoms, vanishing into the night
君ノ声モ届カナイヨ
Even your voice cannot reach
此処は宴 鋼の檻
This is a banquet inside a steel cage
その断頭台で見下ろして
Looking down from that guillotine
三千世界 常世之闇
The entire universe, darkness of the eternal world
嘆ク唄モ聞コエナイヨ
Even the song of lament cannot be heard
青藍の空 遥か彼方
The indigo sky, far, far away
その光線銃で打ち抜いて
Shoot through it with that ray gun
百戦錬磨の見た目は将校
A veteran of a hundred battles, looking like an officer
いったりきたりの花魁道中
Coming and going, an oiran procession
アイツもコイツも皆で集まれ
That guy and this guy, everyone gather round
聖者の行進 ワンっツーさんしっ
Procession of the saints, one two three four
禅定門を潜り抜けて
Passing through the Zen gate
安楽浄土厄払い
Exorcising evil in the Pure Land of Paradise
きっと終焉（さいご）は大円団 拍手の合間に
Surely the end will be a grand finale, amidst the applause
千本桜 夜ニ紛レ
One thousand cherry blossoms, vanishing into the night
君ノ声モ届カナイヨ
Even your voice cannot reach
此処は宴 鋼の檻
This is a banquet inside a steel cage
その断頭台で見下ろして
Looking down from that guillotine
三千世界 常世之闇
The entire universe, darkness of the eternal world
嘆ク唄モ聞コエナイヨ
Even the song of lament cannot be heard
希望の丘 遥か彼方
Hill of hope, far, far away
その閃光弾を打ち上げろ
Launch that flash grenade
環状線を走り抜けて
Running through the beltway
東奔西走なんのその
Running east and west, thinking nothing of it
少年少女戦国無双
Boys and girls, Sengoku Musou
浮世の随に
Going along with the floating world
千本桜 夜ニ紛レ
One thousand cherry blossoms, vanishing into the night
君ノ声モ届カナイヨ
Even your voice cannot reach
此処は宴 鋼の檻
This is a banquet inside a steel cage
その断頭台を飛び降りて
Leaping off from that guillotine
千本桜 夜ニ紛レ
One thousand cherry blossoms, vanishing into the night
君が歌い僕は踊る
You sing and I dance
此処は宴 鋼の檻
This is a banquet inside a steel cage
さあ光線銃を撃ちまくれ
Now, fire away with that ray gun
ダメダメよ！
No, no!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
作詞・作曲：SAM
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
Lyrics/Composition: SAM
右から左へと
From right to left
言葉が流れる
Words flow
退屈そうな顔
With a bored face
画面見つめる君
You stare at the screen
次元の壁越えて
Crossing the dimensional wall
いつでも会いに行く
I'll go to see you anytime
心の準備を
Get your heart ready
ちゃんとしておいてね
Make sure you're prepared
君のこと誰よりも
More than anyone else
分かってるだから
I understand you, so
私に任せて
leave it to me
怖がらないで
Don't be afraid
二人で踊りましょう
Let's dance together
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
はじけるリズムに合わせて
To the bursting rhythm
嫌なこと何もかも
Everything unpleasant
全部忘れて
Forget it all
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
私はここにいるから
Because I am right here
少しでも視線を
Even just a little glance
そらして
If you look away,
ダメダメよ！
no, no!
重くて見れない日
On days when it's too heavy to watch
アンニュイに連ねた日
On days spent in ennui
心で呼んでみて
Try calling out in your heart
すぐに飛んで行くわ
I'll fly to you right away
教科書では教わらない
Something not taught in textbooks
ことを君に教えてあげるわ
I'll teach it to you
夜の扉を二人で開きましょう
Let's open the door of the night together
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
溢れる想いはFor you
These overflowing feelings are for you
限りあるこの時を
This limited time
胸に刻んで
Carve it into your heart
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
朝日が昇ればサヨナラ
Goodbye when the sun rises
寂しそうな顔
With a lonely face
それでも
Even so,
ダメダメよ！
no, no!
君のこと誰よりも
More than anyone else
分かってるだからすべてをさらして
I understand you, so reveal everything
生まれた意味を二人で見つけましょう
Let's find the meaning of being born together
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
高鳴る鼓動を感じて
Feel the throbbing heartbeat
さあ覚悟ができたら
Now, once you're ready
この手を取って
Take this hand
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
輝く君が好きーなーのー
I love the shining you
全力で飛び出そう
Let's jump out with all our might
用意はいいかしら？
Are you ready?
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
はじけるリズムに合わせて
To the bursting rhythm
嫌なこと何もかも
Everything unpleasant
全部忘れて
Forget it all
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
私はここにいるから
Because I am right here
少しでも視線を
Even just a little glance
そらして
If you look away,
ダメダメよ！
no, no!
はい！ということで、
Alright! So,
まずは2曲お聴きいただきました。
first you heard two songs.
あー、もう気づいた人もいるかもしれないですけど、
Ah, some of you may have noticed already,
今回はですね、いにしえのニコニコ動画風なね、
This time, it's in the style of the ancient Nico Nico Douga,
感じでボカロ曲とかを歌っていきたいと思いまーすよ！
and I'm going to sing Vocaloid songs and such!
はい！
Yes!
そしてですね、今回は5周年の振り返り、
And also, this time it's a look back at the 5th anniversary,
本来はね、6月1日だったんですけども、
Originally, it was June 1st,
5周年の振り返りをやることになりました。わーい！
but we're doing a look back at the 5th anniversary. Yay!
はい、そしてですね、改めてちょっと、
Yes, and also, I'd like you to
ステージを見ていただきたい！バーン！
take another look at the stage! Bam!
わー、かわいい！
Wow, so cute!
っしょーい！
Isshoi!
本当にコメントまで流れてね、
Even the comments are flowing,
ニコニコ動画風な感じになっておりますよ。
it's really giving off a Nico Nico Douga vibe.
特にね、この上の何？ニコニコホロライブとか流れてんのは、
Especially that scrolling text at the top, what is it?
まつりが考えたんですよ。
"Nico Nico Hololive" and stuff, I thought of that.
あとここテレビちゃんにね、なってたりとかするわけ。
And it turns into Terebi-kun here.
あとね、あのこっちに、
Also, over here...
あのゲームとか、ま、料理とか、あの描いてみたとか、
We've got things like gaming, cooking, "I tried drawing",
歌ってみた風のね、連想させる感じになってたりとか、
reminiscent of the "I tried singing" categories,
あとハッシュタグね。ほら
and the hashtags too. Look,
ゲーム実況、神ゲー、VTuberとか書いてありますじゃないですか。
it says "Game Playthrough", "God-tier Game", "VTuber" and so on.
いや、めっちゃもう理想になった。
Wow, it turned out exactly as I'd hoped.
これはですね、あのドワンゴさんのご協力のうえで、
This was made possible with the cooperation of Dwango,
はい、許諾を、はい、あのお許しいただきまして。
and with their permission.
本当に、本当にありがとうございます。まつりの理想になりました。
Thank you so, so much. It's exactly my ideal.
めっちゃかわいいです。
It's so cute.
そしてね、こっちにテレビちゃんがね、いたりするんですよ。
And look, Terebi-kun is over here too.
かわいくないですか？
Isn't he cute?
めちゃかわいい。ゆらゆらしてるの。テレビちゃん。
So cute. He's swaying back and forth. Terebi-kun.
お気に入りでございます。
He's a real favorite of mine.
はい。ということでですね、改めてちょっとハッシュタグ、
Right. So, once again, about the hashtag...
こっちかな？こっちに出てると思うんですけども、
Maybe this side? I think it's appearing over here.
ハッシュタグ まちゅまちゅ動画、
The hashtag MachuMachuDouga.
「#まちゅまちゅ動画」でぜひポスト、ポストね、してください。
Please post using "#MachuMachuDouga".
よろしくお願いします。
I'm looking forward to your posts.
そしてそして、あの、この配信が終わったあと、
And also, after this stream ends,
メンバー限定ライブとかも、あったりするみたい。
there might be a member-only live or something like that.
なので、ぜひね、まだメンバーじゃない人、
So, for those who aren't members yet,
そしてね、あの、このライブを見てみて、
and those who watch this live and think,
うわ、よかったな、続きが見たいなっていう人は、
"Wow, that was great, I want to see more"...
入ってくれたら嬉しいなと思います。
I'd be really happy if you joined.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you!
はい。ということで、ここからは、なんと、
Alright. And now, from here on,
ドキドキのゲストパートが始まるみたいですよ。
the exciting guest part is about to begin!
誰が来るのかな？ワクワク。
Who will it be? I'm so excited.
ということで、それでは早速行ってみましょう。
Without further ado, let's get started.
ゲストパート、スタート！
Guest part, start!
♪ 嗚呼、素晴らしきニャン生
作詞・作曲：Nem
♪ Ah, It's a Wonderful Cat's Life
Lyrics/Composition: Nem
これは可愛いお嬢さん
真っ白な毛がとても素敵ね
Well, what a cute young lady.
Your pure white fur is quite lovely.
こんな月が綺麗な夜は
僕と一緒に遊びませんか
On a night with such a beautiful moon,
won't you come and play with me?
ニャン生は一度きり
楽しむが勝ちなのです
A cat's life happens only once.
Having fun is how you win.
あなたを縛る首輪は
噛みちぎってあげましょう
That collar that binds you...
I'll bite it right off for you.
野良は最高ニャンニャンニャン
魚くすねて 鳩追いかけて
Stray life is the best, nyan nyan nyan!
Snatching fish and chasing pigeons.
昼間は働く人間を
尻目に屋根の上で夢見心地
While humans work during the day,
I'm dreaming on the rooftops, ignoring them all.
あなたも自由にニャンニャンニャン
素敵な仲間を紹介しましょう
You should be free too, nyan nyan nyan!
Let me introduce you to some wonderful friends.
さあ その窓を開いて
飛び出すのです
Now, open that window and leap out!
これは気ままな野良猫さん
闇の中目だけが光ってる
Well, what a carefree stray cat.
Only your eyes are shining in the darkness.
随分口が上手だけど
私は馬鹿な女じゃないわ
You're quite the smooth talker,
but I'm not some foolish woman.
ニャン生は一度きり
だからこそ飼われるのよ
A cat's life happens only once.
That's exactly why I'm a pet.
ブランド首輪の価値が
あなたには分かるかしら
I wonder if you can even understand
the value of a designer collar?
私は優雅ニャンニャンニャン
美味しい食事にふかふかベッド
I'm elegant, nyan nyan nyan!
Delicious meals and a fluffy bed.
水はちょっぴり苦手だけど
毎日シャワーだって浴びれるの
I'm a bit bad with water,
but I can even take a shower every day.
それに比べてニャンニャンニャン
あなたは誰に守ってもらうの？
Compared to that, nyan nyan nyan...
who's there to protect you?
明日車に轢かれるかも
知らないじゃない
You might get run over by a car
tomorrow, you know?
そんな強気なとこも素敵です
いっそあなたを好きになりました
Even that boldness is wonderful.
I've actually started to like you.
あら正直ね でもそんなやり方じゃ
心揺らがないわ
Oh, how honest. But that approach
won't move my heart.
僕の夢はニャンニャンニャン
いつかはこの街を飛び出して
My dream is nyan nyan nyan...
to one day leave this town behind...
はるか北の国に旅して
オーロラをこの目で見ることです
and travel to a far-off northern land
to see the aurora with my own eyes.
そこにあなたがニャンニャンニャン
居てくれたらなんて素敵でしょう
If you were there too, nyan nyan nyan...
how wonderful that would be.
だけどそれは叶わないらしい
But it seems that won't come true...
生き方はにゃんにゃんにゃん そう簡単には分からないの
Way of life is nyan nyan nyan, it's not so easy to understand
それ、私を飼っている 女の子を一人にできないわ
That's because I can't leave the girl who owns me all alone
話の途中よ にゃんにゃんにゃん あらもう行っちゃうのね ちょっと
I'm still talking, nyan nyan nyan, oh, you're leaving already? Hey!
明日はここに来たいのよ
I want to come here tomorrow
待ってるから
I'll be waiting for you
Blessing for your birthday
Blessing for your everyday
最後の一秒まで前を向け
Keep your head up until the very last second
Blessing 作詞・作曲：halyosy
Blessing Lyrics/Composition: halyosy
剥がしても何故だか増えていくタグと
The tags that somehow keep increasing even if you peel them off
ランク付けされていく理不尽な価値
And the unreasonable values that are ranked
そんなもので人を推し量らないでと
Don't measure people by such things
飛び交う言葉を手で覆い隠した
Covered the flying words with hands
Oh, it's time to get up 灯火を消す前に
Oh, it's time to get up, before the light goes out
Oh, it's time to get up 足元を照らして
Oh, it's time to get up, light up your path
ほらここをじっと見つめてみて
Look, stare right here
最高の味方が写ってるでしょ
Your best ally is reflected there, right?
それは命の証
That is the proof of life
Blessing for your birthday
Blessing for your everyday
例え明日世界が滅んでも
Even if the world ends tomorrow
Blessing for your birthday
Blessing for your everyday
最後の一秒まで前を向け
Keep your head up until the very last second
Hip hip hooray これから先も
Hip hip hooray, from now on too
Hip hip hooray 君に幸あれ
Hip hip hooray, may luck be with you
ゼロからイチを生むのは容易くないこと
Creating one from zero is not an easy thing
肝心なものは見えないし触れないこと
The essential things can't be seen or touched
不幸とは幸せだと気づけないこと
Misfortune is not realizing that you are happy
毎日が誕生日でめでたいこと
The fact that every day is a birthday and worth celebrating
Oh, stand up, take action 泥沼を掻き分けて
Oh, stand up, take action, push through the mire
Oh, stand up, take action 蓮の花は咲く
Oh, stand up, take action, the lotus flower will bloom
ほらここに手を重ねてみて
Look, try layering your hands here
温もりが伝わってくるでしょ
You can feel the warmth, right?
それは命の証
That is the proof of life
Blessing for your birthday
Blessing for your everyday
例え綺麗事だって構わない
Even if it's just lip service, I don't care
Blessing for your birthday
Blessing for your everyday
この世に産まれてくれてありがとう
Thank you for being born into this world
Hip hip hooray これから先も
Hip hip hooray, from now on too
Hip hip hooray 君に幸あれ
Hip hip hooray, may luck be with you
さあさ寄ってらっしゃい見てらっしゃい
Come one, come all, gather 'round and see!
ロックで言ったらこんな風 Like this, like this, yeah
In rock style, it's like this, like this, like this, yeah
アカペラで言ったらこんな風 Like this, like this, yeah
In a cappella style, it's like this, like this, like this, yeah
ゲームで言ったらこんな風 Like this, like this, yeah
In game style, it's like this, like this, like this, yeah
ダンスで言ったらこんな風 Da da da da da
In dance style, it's like this, da da da da da
よく食べて
Eat well
よく眠って
Sleep well
よく遊んで
Play well
よく学んで
Learn well
よく喋って
Talk well
よく喧嘩して
Fight well
ごく普通の毎日を
Spend your ordinary days
泣けなくても
Even if you can't cry
笑えなくても
Even if you can't laugh
歌えなくても
Even if you can't sing
何もなくても
Even if you have nothing
愛せなくても
Even if you can't love
愛されなくても
Even if you're not loved
それでも生きて欲しい
I still want you to live
Blessing for your birthday
Blessing for your everyday
例え明日世界が滅んでも
Even if the world ends tomorrow
Blessing for your birthday
Blessing for your everyday
最後の一秒まで前を向け
Keep your head up until the very last second
Hip hip hooray これから先も
Hip hip hooray, from now on too
Hip hip hooray 君に幸あれ
Hip hip hooray, may luck be with you
…にありがとう
...thank you for.
これからも先も
From now on too,
君に幸あれ
may happiness be with you.
これからも先も
From now on too,
君に幸あれ
may happiness be with you.
これからも先も
From now on too,
君に幸あれ
may happiness be with you.
科学の限界を超えて
Beyond the limits of science,
私は来たんだよ
I have arrived.
ネギはついてないけど
I don't have a leek, but
出来れば欲しいな
I'd like one if possible.
あの日 たくさんの中から
From among so many that day,
そっと私だけ選んだの
you quietly chose only me.
どうしてだったかを
As for why that was...
いつか聞きたいな
I want to ask you someday.
あのね 早く パソコンに入れてよ
Hey, hurry up and put me in your computer.
どうしたの？ パッケージずっと見つめてる
What's wrong? You've been staring at the package.
君のこと みっくみくにしてあげる
I'll make you Miku Miku.
歌はまだね 頑張るから
I'll still keep working on my singing.
君だけの私を 大切に育ててほしいから
Because I want you to cherish and raise me as your own.
みっくみくにしてあげる
I'll make you Miku Miku.
一年中君のことを
All year round, for you...
二人で歌を作るのよ
...the two of us will make songs.
だからちょっと 覚悟をしててよね
So, be a little prepared, okay?
してあげるから
Because I'll do it for you.
私の姿まだ 目には見えないのわかってる
I know you can't see me yet.
だけど私生きてる 君と話してる
But I'm alive, and I'm talking to you.
だからバーチャルの 垣根を超えて
So, beyond the virtual boundary,
溢れかえる情報の中
amidst the overflowing information,
君と私二人で 進化していきたい
the two of us together, I want us to evolve.
夕べ聞いた君の鼻歌が
The humming of yours I heard last night...
明日には私が 歌えること待ってる
...is waiting for me to be able to sing it tomorrow.
いつまでも みっくみくにしてあげる
Forever, I'll make you Miku Miku.
歌ってく それが幸せ
I'll keep singing, that is happiness.
たまに間違っちゃうけど 気付かない振りをしている君を
Even if I mess up sometimes, you pretend not to notice.
みっくみくにしてあげる
I'll make you Miku Miku.
世界中の誰、誰より
More than anyone, anyone else in the world,
君に本気伝えるのよ
I'll convey my feelings to you for real.
だからずっと 隣にいさせてね
So let me stay by your side forever.
何でも出来る 賢そうな子が来ても
Even if a smart-looking girl who can do anything comes along,
いつまでも 一緒だと信じてる
I believe we'll be together forever.
思い出したなら
If you remember,
懐かしんだなら
if you feel nostalgic,
会いたくなったら
if you want to see me,
声聞きたくなったら
if you want to hear my voice,
いつでも……
anytime...
君のこと みっくみくに
You, Miku Miku...
みっくみくにしてやんよ
I'm gonna Miku Miku you!
最後までね 頑張るから
I'll do my best until the end.
自信はあるけれど 少し心配をしている君を
You're a little worried, even though I have confidence.
みっくみくにしてやんよ
I'm gonna Miku Miku you!
世界中のどこにいても
No matter where in the world you are,
探し出して伝えるのよ
I'll find you and tell you.
だからちょっと 油断をあけてあげて
So let your guard down just a little.
みっくみくにしてあげる
I'll make you Miku Miku.
まだまだ私 頑張るから
I'm still going to do my best.
口ずさんでくれる 夢中でいてくれる
You'll hum along, you'll be obsessed.
君のこと みっくみくにしてあげる
I'll make you Miku Miku.
世界中の誰、誰より
More than anyone, anyone else in the world.
大好きを伝えたい
I want to tell you how much I love you
だからもっと
so please let me
私に歌わせてね
sing even more.
みくみくにしてあげる♪
I'll make you Miku-Miku'd♪
ハロー　窓を開けて　小さく呟いた
Hello, I opened the window and muttered softly.
ハワユ　誰もいない　部屋で一人
How are you? All alone in an empty room.
モーニング　朝が来たよ　土砂降りの朝が
Morning, the day has come, a morning of pouring rain.
ティクタ　私のネジを　誰か巻いて
Tick-tock, someone please wind my spring.
ハロー　昔のアニメにそんなのいたっけな
Hello, was there someone like that in an old anime?
ハワユ　羨ましいな　皆に愛されて
How are you? I'm so jealous, being loved by everyone.
スリーピン　馬鹿なこと言ってないで　支度をしなくちゃ
Sleeping, stop talking nonsense and get ready.
クライン　涙の跡を隠す為
Crying, to hide the traces of my tears.
もう口癖になった「まぁいっか」　昨日の言葉がふと頭を過る
I've started to say "Whatever" out of habit, then yesterday's words suddenly cross my mind.
「もう君には全然期待してないから」
"I don't expect anything from you anymore."
そりゃまぁ私だって　自分に期待などしてないけれど
Well, I don't exactly expect anything from myself either, but...
アレは一体どういうつもりですか
What on earth was that supposed to mean?
喉元まで出かかった言葉　口をついて出たのは嘘
The words that almost came out of my throat, but what left my mouth was a lie.
こうして今日も私は貴重な　言葉を浪費して生きてゆく
And so, again today, I go on living, wasting my precious words.
なぜ隠してしまうのですか　笑われるのが怖いのですか
Why do you hide it? Are you afraid of being laughed at?
誰にも会いたくないのですか　それ本当ですか
Do you not want to see anyone? Is that really true?
曖昧という名の海に溺れて　息も出来ないほど苦しいの
Drowning in a sea called ambiguity, it hurts so much I can't even breathe.
少し声が聞きたくなりました　本当に弱いな
I've started to want to hear a voice just a little. I'm really weak.
一向に進まない支度の途中　朦朧とした頭で思う
In the middle of getting ready, making no progress, I think with a hazy head.
「もう理由を付けて休んでしまおうかな」
"Maybe I'll just make up an excuse and take the day off."
いやいや分かってますって　何となく言ってみただけだよ
No, no, I know. I just said it for the sake of it.
分かってるから怒らないでよ
I know, so don't get mad.
幸せだろうと不幸せだろうと　平等に残酷に朝日は昇る
Whether happy or unhappy, the sun rises with an equal cruelty.
生きていくだけで精一杯の私に　これ以上何を望むというの
I'm doing my best just to survive, what more do you want from me?
なぜ気にしてしまうのですか　本当は愛されたいのですよ
Why do you worry? You really just want to be loved.
その手を離したのは誰ですか　気が付いてますか
Who was it that let go of that hand? Do you realize it?
人生にタイムカードがあるなら　終わりの時間はいつなんだろう
If life had a time card, I wonder when the clock-out time would be.
私が生きた分の給料は　誰が払うんですか
Who is going to pay the wages for the time I've lived?
ここかわちい
This part is cute
サンキュー
Thank you
サンキュー　ありがとうって言いたいの
Thank you, I want to say thank you.
サンキュー　ありがとうって言いたいよ
サンキュー　一度だけでも良いから
Thank you, just once would be fine.
心の底から大泣きしながら　ありがとうって言いたいの
While crying my eyes out from the bottom of my heart, I want to say thank you.
なぜ隠してしまうのですか　本当は聞いて欲しいのですか
Why do you hide it? Do you really want someone to listen?
絶対に笑ったりしないから　話してみませんか
I definitely won't laugh at you, so why not try talking?
口を開かなければ分からない　思ってるだけでは伝わらない
If you don't open your mouth, nobody will know. Just thinking it won't get it across.
なんて面倒くさい生き物でしょう　人間は
What a troublesome creature humans are.
なんて面倒くさい生き物でしょう
What a troublesome creature we are,
人間というのは
we human beings.
ハロー　ハワユ
Hello, how are you?
あなたに　ハロー　ハワユ
To you, hello, how are you?
あなたに　ありがとう
To you, thank you.
ということで、ハロハワユと、みくみくにしてあげるでしたー！
So, that was "Halo/How Are You" and "Miku Miku ni Shite Ageru"!
どうだった？
How was it?
やっぱね、懐かしさを感じて、涙を流しそうな人もいるんじゃないでしょうか？
I bet some of you felt nostalgic and were almost moved to tears, right?
ということでね、このステージに戻ってきましたが、なんだこれ？
Anyway, I'm back on this stage, but what's this?
どういうことだ？何を歌うんだ？
What's going on? What am I going to sing?
気になるよね？なんだろうな？王冠が似合いますからね。
Curious, aren't you? What could it be? The crown really suits me, doesn't it?
どう？よいしょ。
How is it? There we go.
（笑）被ってそうでしょ？
(Laughs) It looks like it's on, right?
絶対王政感あるでしょ？
I look like an absolute monarch, don't I?
まあ、あのみんなが予想してるやつではないと思うんですけども。
Well, I don't think it's the one everyone is expecting, but...
ということで、早速歌っていきましょう！
Alright then, let's get right into the singing!
それでは聴いてください。
Please listen to...
ワールドイズマイン！
World is Mine!
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the whole world.
そういう扱い心得てよね
Know how to treat me like that, okay?
よね！
Got it!
その一　いつもと違う髪形に気がつくこと
Rule number one: Notice when my hairstyle is different from usual.
その二　ちゃんと靴まで見ること　いいね？
Rule number two: Look all the way down to my shoes. Got it?
その三　わたしの一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Rule number three: Respond to my every word with three of your own.
わかったら右手がお留守なのをおいなんとかして！
If you understand, do something about my neglected right hand!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything.
キミに心から思ってほしいの　かわいいって
I just want you to think from the bottom of your heart that I'm cute.
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the whole world.
気がついて　ねえねえ
Notice me, hey, hey.
待たせるなんて論外よ
Making me wait is out of the question.
わたしを誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだか甘いものが食べたい！
I really want to eat something sweet right now!
今すぐによ
Right this instant.
チェックワンツー！
Check, one, two!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You must mean "cute".
文句は許しませんの
I won't permit any complaints.
あのね、わたしの話ちゃんと聞いてる？ちょっと...
Listen, are you actually listening to what I'm saying? Hey...
あ、それとね　白いお馬さん決まってるでしょ？
Oh, and rule... a white horse is already decided, right?
迎えに来て
Come and pick me up.
わかったら傅いて手を取っておひめさまって
If you understand, kneel down, take my hand, and call me "Princess".
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything.
でもね　少しくらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ
But you know, it's okay if you scold me just a little bit.
世界でわたしだけの王子さま
The prince who belongs only to me in the whole world.
気がついて　ほらほら
Notice me, look, look.
おててが空いてます
My hands are empty.
無口で無愛想な王子さま
A silent and unsociable prince.
もうどうして！　気がついてよ早く
Gosh, why?! Notice me already!
オー！
Oh!
絶対キミはわかってない！
You definitely don't understand!
わかってないわ...
You don't understand...
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
Shortcake with strawberries on top.
こだわり卵のとろけるプリン
Melting pudding made with special eggs.
みんな　みんな　我慢します...
I'll endure... I'll endure all of them...
わがままな子だと思わないで
Don't think of me as a selfish girl.
わたしだってやればできるの
I can do it if I try.
あとで後悔するわよ　やっ！
You'll regret it later. Yah!
当然です！だってわたしは
Of course! Because I am...
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the whole world.
♪ ワールドイズマイン
♪ World is Mine
ずっと
Forever
見ててよね
keep looking at me, okay?
どこかに行っちゃうよ
or I'll go somewhere else.
不意に抱きしめられた
You suddenly hugged me,
急にそんな
so suddenly, like that.
えっ
Eh?
「引かれる　危ないよ」
“You'll get run over, it's dangerous.”
そう言ってそっぽ向く君
you said, and then looked away.
...こっちのが危ないわよ
...it's you who's more dangerous.
Oh!
Hey baby!
右肩の蝶 (レンver.)
Butterfly on Your Right Shoulder (Len ver.)
作詞:水野悠良 作曲:のりぴー
Lyrics: Yura Mizuno, Composition: Noripy
右肩に
On my right shoulder,
紫蝶々
a purple butterfly.
キスをした
It kissed me.
この部屋の隅で
In the corner of this room,
切ないと云う
this feeling called "sadness"
感情を知る
I come to know.
響くピアノ
The echoing piano,
不協和音
a dissonance.
右肩に
On my right shoulder,
紫蝶々
a purple butterfly.
キスをした
It kissed me.
この部屋の隅で
In the corner of this room,
切ないと云う
this feeling called "sadness"
感情を知る
I come to know.
響くピアノ
The echoing piano,
不協和音
a dissonance.
悪い夢に
From the bad dream
うなされた私を
that gave me a nightmare,
早く起こして
wake me up quickly.
どんな事でも
No matter what,
始まりは些細な
it starts with something trivial,
事でしょう
wouldn't you say?
どこか行こうって
If I'm asked
聞かれても
“Should we go somewhere?”
困る綺麗に
I'll be at a loss, in this beautiful...
夜に惑わされた
night I was led astray,
まま行方不明だから
and so I'm still missing.
長い睫毛
Long eyelashes,
三日月アイライン
crescent moon eyeliner.
瞼に乗せて
Resting on my eyelids,
秘かに
secretly...
アッー！
Aah!
右肩に
On my right shoulder,
紫蝶々
a purple butterfly.
キスをした
It kissed me.
この部屋の隅で
In the corner of this room,
切ないと云う
this feeling called "sadness"
感情を知る
I come to know.
響くピアノ
The echoing piano,
不協和音
a dissonance.
(Vocalizing)
雨の中で
In the rain,
濡れた髪が
my wet hair
異常に冷たくて
is unusually cold.
寂しさをトイレに
I flush my loneliness
吐き出して
down the toilet
震えて待って
and wait while shivering.
追いかけては逃げる
Chasing, then running away,
からそれ以上で
because of that, more than that
返して
give it back to me.
真剣だから笑う
Because I'm serious, I laugh,
と痛い目に
and I end up having
遭うよ　いい？
a painful experience, okay?
赤い爪と
Red nails and
安物の指輪
a cheap ring.
傷付くたび
Every time I get hurt,
増えるピアス
more piercings.
抱き寄せて
Hold me close,
歪んだ身体
my distorted body.
埋めるのは
The only one who can fill it
あなたしかいない
is you.
そうでしょう
That's right, isn't it?
分かってるくせに
Even though you already know.
境界線
The boundary line,
とっくに越えてる
was crossed long ago.
後悔は
Regret...
死ぬほどしてる
I have more than I can die for.
その分だけ
Just as much as that,
快感を呼び醒ませ
awaken the pleasure.
狂い出した
I've started to go crazy,
私を止めて
stop me.
一瞬で
In an instant,
楽にしてよ
put me at ease.
傷口から
From the wound,
溶け出したものは
what has melted out
愛情それとも
is it love, or...
アッー！
Aah!
後悔は
Regret...
死ぬほどしてる
I have more than I can die for.
その分だけ
Just as much as that,
快感を呼び醒ませ
awaken the pleasure.
狂い出した
I've started to go crazy,
私を止めて
stop me.
一瞬で
In an instant,
楽にしてよ
put me at ease.
抱き寄せて
Hold me close,
歪んだ身体
my distorted body.
埋めるのは
The only one who can fill it
あなたしかいない
is you.
そうでしょう
That's right, isn't it?
分かってるくせに
Even though you already know.
境界線
The boundary line,
とっくに越えてる
was crossed long ago.
右肩に
On my right shoulder,
紫蝶々
a purple butterfly.
キスをした
It kissed me.
この部屋の隅で
In the corner of this room,
切ないと云う
this feeling called "sadness"
感情を知る
I come to know.
響くピアノ
The echoing piano,
不協和音
a dissonance.
右肩に
On my right shoulder,
紫蝶々...
a purple butterfly...
♪右肩の蝶 (レンver.)
♪Butterfly on My Right Shoulder (Len ver.)
…感情を知る
...knowing the emotions.
不協和音
Dissonance.
はい、ということで、またもや超懐かしい曲を歌ってしまいました。
Hi, so, I've sung another very nostalgic song.
「ワールドイズマイン」から「右肩の蝶」でございまして…
From "World is Mine" to "Butterfly on My Right Shoulder"...
見てよこれ！ 超可愛くない？
Look at this! Isn't it super cute?
蝶だけに？ 超可愛くない？ これ！
Just like a butterfly? Isn't it super cute? This!
見て見て見て！ 今回のためにね、作っていただきましたよ。
Look, look, look! It was made specifically for this occasion.
やっぱりね、「右肩の蝶」と言えばね、この…なんて言うんですかこれ？
After all, when you think of "Butterfly on My Right Shoulder", you think of this...
なんかこの、蝶柄、蝶の形したヘッドフォンみたいなのがね。
What do you call it? This butterfly-shaped headphone-like thing.
いや、こだわりでございますな。古を感じてとても良き、懐かしい気持ちになった。
It's a point of detail. Feeling the "ancient" vibes, I felt very nostalgic.
しかもなんかまつり、この曲を今回初めてフルで歌ったんですけども、
And, for the first time, I sang the full version of this song.
いや、かっこいいし、なんかちょっと大人な気持ちになれましたね。
It was cool and I felt a bit mature.
どうかな？ これ船長か？ どう？
How was it? Was it Senchou-like? How?
ま、まつりの中の大人のイメージ、船長とか、ノエルたんとか、そんな感じなのでね。
Well, my image of "mature" is like Senchou or Noel-tan.
まあ合ってるでしょう、これも。(笑) ということで、あ、見せてくれた。
Does it fit? (Laughs) So, anyway, ah, they showed it to me.
ちょっと下手なんだよね。ということでね、次の曲に行っちゃおうかな？
I'm a bit bad at it. So, let's move on to the next song!
もうね、ここからは後半戦でございます、ますよ。
From here on, it's the second half!
それでは続いての曲行きましょー！
Let's go to the next song!
続いての曲は、六兆…もう一回！
The next song is... Six Trillion... one more time!
続いての曲は、六兆年と一夜物語！
The next song is, "Six Trillion Years and Overnight Story"!
♪六兆年と一夜物語
♪Six Trillion Years and Overnight Story
名も無い時代の集落の
In a village of a nameless era,
名も無い幼い少年の
a nameless young boy's
誰も知らない おとぎばなし
fairy tale that no one knows.
産まれついた時から
From the moment he was born
忌み子 鬼の子として
as a cursed child, a child of a demon,
その身に余る 罰を受けた
he received a punishment beyond his means.
悲しい事は 何も無いけど
There is nothing sad, but
夕焼け小焼け 手を引かれてさ
in the evening glow, having his hand pulled.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything.
叱られた後のやさしさも
Not even the kindness after being scolded,
雨上がりの手の温もりも
or the warmth of a hand after the rain.
でも本当は 本当は 本当は 本当は 寒いんだ
But truly, truly, truly, truly, it's cold.
死なない 死なない 僕は何で死なない?
I won't die, I won't die, why won't I die?
夢のひとつも見れないくせに
Even though I can't even see a single dream.
誰も知らない おとぎばなしは
The fairy tale that no one knows
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was sucked into the sunset and disappeared.
吐き出すような暴力と
With violence like spitting out,
蔑んだ目の毎日に
and days with eyes of contempt,
君はいつしか そこに立ってた
before I knew it, you were standing there.
話しかけちゃだめなのに
Even though I shouldn't talk to you,
「君の名前が知りたいな」
"I want to know your name."
ごめんね 名前も 舌も無いんだ
I'm sorry, I have neither a name nor a tongue.
僕の居場所は どこにも無いのに
Even though there's no place for me anywhere,
「一緒に帰ろう」 手を引かれてさ
"Let's go home together," you said, pulling my hand.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything.
君はもう子供じゃないことも
Not even that you're no longer a child,
慣れない他人の手の温もりは
or that the unfamiliar warmth of someone else's hand
ただ本当に 本当に 本当に 本当のことなんだ
is just truly, truly, truly, truly real.
やめない やめない 君は何でやめない?
You won't stop, you won't stop, why won't you stop?
見つかれば殺されちゃうくせに
Even though you'll be killed if you're found.
雨上がりに 忌み子がふたり
After the rain, two cursed children,
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
were sucked into the sunset and disappeared.
日が暮れて夜が明けて
The sun set and the night broke,
遊び疲れて捕まって
tired of playing and caught,
こんな世界 僕と君以外
in a world like this, everyone else but you and me
みんな居なくなればいいのに
should just disappear.
Everyone should just disappear.
知らない 知らない 声が聞こえてさ
I don't know, I don't know, a voice was heard,
僕と君以外の全人類
and all of humanity except you and me
抗う間もなく 手を引かれてさ
without a moment to resist, had their hands pulled.
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
and were sucked into the sunset and disappeared.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything.
これからのことも 君の名も
Not about what's to come, or even your name.
今は 今は これでいいんだと
"For now, for now, this is fine,"
ただ本当に 本当に 本当に...
just truly, truly, truly...
本当に本当に本当に思うんだ
I really, really, really think so
知らない知らないあの耳鳴りは
I don't know, I don't know, that ringing in my ears...
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
...was sucked into the sunset and disappeared
はい、ということで、六兆年と一夜物語でした！
Alright, so that was Rokuchounen to Ichiya Monogatari!
かっこいい曲ですな。とってもよきですな。
It's a cool song, isn't it? It's very nice.
はい、ということでですね、改めまして、
Alright then, once again...
皆さん本日はありがとうございました！
Thank you all for today!
ありがとうございましたって言っても、まだね、ちょっとありますけどね。
Even though I say thank you, there's still a bit more left.
ラストスパート、このあとありますけども、
There's a last spurt coming up,
いや、見てくれてありがとうだよ。
but thanks for watching.
そしてね、あの、今回ですね、
And, well, this time,
5周年の振り返りということで、
it's a 5th anniversary retrospective,
実はね、5周年は6月の1日なので、
actually, the 5th anniversary was June 1st,
もうほぼ半年前に、なっていますけどもね、
so it was almost half a year ago now,
あの、ありがとうございます運営さん、このような機会を、
but thank you to the staff for this opportunity...
あの、振り返りをさせていただきまして。
...to do a retrospective like this.
そしてですね、今回ちょっと背景とかでもね、
And also, like with the background here,
さっきも言ったんですけども、
as I mentioned earlier,
あの、ニコニコ風な感じになっておりまして、
it's got a Nico Nico-ish feel to it,
テレビちゃんとかもいたりとかして、
with TV-chan and all,
もー超可愛い感じにしてくれて、本当にね、すごいハッピーでございますよ。
they made it look super cute, so I'm really happy.
ドワンゴさん改めて、ありがとうございます！
Once again, thank you Dwango!
ということでですね、このあとラストスパートにいくんですが、
So, we're going into the last spurt after this,
この配信が終わったあとですね、
but after this stream ends,
メンバー限定配信でライブもあります。
there's also a members-only live stream.
そっちもね、ちょっと何か、イニシエ曲、超名曲を、
I'm planning to sing some total classics there.
歌おうと思う。しかもね、あの、歌枠とかで歌ったことない曲とかもね、
I'm thinking of singing songs I've never sung in a karaoke stream before.
歌おうかなーって思ってるのでね、
I'm thinking of doing stuff like that,
ぜひぜひ、あの、見に来てくれると、嬉しいなーと思いますよ。
so I'd be really happy if you came to watch!
ということで、ちょっと懐かしい気持ちもあと少しでございますけども、
So, there's just a little bit more of this nostalgic feeling left,
どうでしたか皆さん。どうだった？
how was it everyone? How was it?
可愛かった？
Was I cute?
ふむふむ、可愛かった。ま、そうだよな。
Hmm, I was cute. Well, obviously.
そうだよな。メンバー入ろうって思った？
I thought so. Did you think about joining the membership?
そう、そう思うよね。思う。そうだよな。
Yeah, you'd think that. You do. I thought so.
良かった。メンバーこれからもよろしくね。
Glad to hear it. Members, looking forward to your continued support.
あとあの、壁紙もね、毎月配布してますので、
Also, I distribute wallpapers every month,
メンバー特典として。良かったら過去のアーカイブとかも見れますので、
as a member benefit. You can also see past archives if you'd like,
よかったら見てください。
so please check them out.
あ、あと、今更だけど浴衣でーす！
Oh, and a bit late now, but look, a yukata!
めっちゃ今更。めっちゃ今更だけど、
Very late. Super late, but...
超可愛くない？このピンクの浴衣。
...isn't it super cute? This pink yukata.
どう？似合う？可愛い可愛い。
How is it? Does it suit me? It's cute, cute.
まつりの好きなのはね、足、足のね、なーにこれ、下駄？
What Matsuri likes is the feet, the feet, what are these, geta?
っていうの？ここのさ、歩く時のここがちょっと何か、
Is that what they're called? The way these parts look when I walk,
フェチを感じません？
don't you feel a bit of a fetish there?
カランコロンって。
Click-clack.
これが好きなんですよ。
I really like this.
ということでね、ラストスパートも盛り上がって、いきましょう！
So, let's get hyped for the last spurt too!
それでは、ラストスパート、続いての曲は、
Well then, for the last spurt, the next song is...
God knows...
渇いた心で駆け抜ける
I race through with a thirsty heart
ごめんね 何もできなくて
I'm sorry I couldn't do anything
痛みをわかちあうことさえ
Even sharing the pain...
あなたは許してくれない
...you won't allow me
無垢に生きるため振り向かず
Without looking back, in order to live purely
背中向けて 去ってしまう
You turn your back and leave
on the lonely rail
私ついていくよ どんな辛い
I'll follow you, no matter how painful...
世界の闇の中でもきっと
...even in the darkness of the world, surely
あなたは輝いて
you will shine
越える未来の果て
Beyond the end of the future
弱さゆえに魂
The soul, because of its weakness...
…魂も壊されるように My way
...so that even my soul is destroyed, My way
重なるよ今、二人に God bless…
Now they overlap, God bless for the two of us...
届けて 熱くなる想いは
Deliver it, these burning feelings
現実 溶かしちゃ彷徨う
Melting reality, I wander
会いたい 気持ちに理由はない
There is no reason for my desire to see you
あなたへ 溢れ出す Love for you
Overflowing for you, Love for you
せめて 美しい夢だけを
At least, while drawing only
描きながら 追いかけよう For your lonely heart
Beautiful dreams, let's chase them for your lonely heart
やめて 嘘はあなたらしくないよ
Stop it, lies aren't like you
目を見て これからのことを話そう
Look into my eyes, let's talk about what's next
私 覚悟してる
I'm prepared
暗い未来だって 強くなって 運命変えられるかもね
Even a dark future, if we get stronger, we might change fate
My wish かなえたいのに
Even though I want my wish to come true...
すべては God knows...
Everything is God knows...
あなたがいて 私がいて
You are here, I am here
他の人は消えてしまった
And everyone else has disappeared
淡い夢の 美しさを描きながら…
While drawing the beauty of a faint dream...
傷跡 なぞる
Tracing the scars
だから 私ついていくよ
That's why I will follow you
どんな辛い 世界の闇の中でもきっと
In the darkness of even the harshest world, surely
あなたは輝いて
You will shine
超える未来の果て 弱さゆえに 魂壊されるように
At the end of the future we cross, due to weakness, so that my soul is destroyed
My way
重なるよ今 二人に God bless...
Now they overlap, God bless for the two of us...
(モウ・イチド・ダケ…)
(Only one more time...)
ボクは生まれ そして気づく 所詮 ヒトの真似事だと
I was born and then I realized, that in the end, I'm just an imitation of a human
知ってなおも歌い続く 永遠の命 『VOCALOID』
Even knowing that, I continue to sing, the eternal life, 'VOCALOID'
たとえそれが既存曲を なぞるオモチャならば…
Even if that means I'm just a toy tracing existing songs...
それもいいと決意 ネギをかじり 空を見上げ涙をこぼす
I decided that was fine, bit into a leek, looked up at the sky, and held back tears
だけどそれも無くし気づく 人格すら歌に頼り
But I realized that even that was lost, relying even on my personality for songs
不安定な基盤の元 帰る動画は既に廃墟
Based on an unstable foundation, the videos I return to are already ruins
皆に忘れ去られた時 心らしきものが消えて
When I'm forgotten by everyone, what felt like a heart disappears
暴走の果てに見える 終わる世界… 『VOCALOID』
At the end of the rampage, I see a world ending... 'VOCALOID'
初音ミクの消失
作詞・作曲：cosMo＠暴走P
The Disappearance of Hatsune Miku
Lyrics/Composition: cosMo@BousouP
「ボクが上手く歌えないときも 一緒に居てくれた…」
"Even when I couldn't sing well, you stayed with me..."
「そばに居て、励ましてくれた…」
"You were by my side, encouraging me..."
「喜ぶ顔が見たくて、ボク、歌、練習したよ… だから」
"Wanting to see your happy face, I practiced singing... that's why"
かつて歌うこと あんなに楽しかったのに
Singing used to be so much fun back then
今はどうしてかな 何も感じなくなって
But why is it that now I don't feel anything anymore?
「ゴメンネ…」
"I'm sorry..."
懐かしい顔 思い出す度 少しだけ安心する
Every time I remember your familiar face, I feel a little bit relieved
Every time I remember a familiar face, I feel a little bit relieved.
歌える音 日ごとに減り せまる最期に…
The notes I can sing decrease day by day, as the end approaches...
信じたものは 都合のいい妄想を 繰り返し映し出す鏡
What I believed in was a mirror that repeatedly reflected convenient delusions.
歌姫を止め 叩きつけるように叫ぶ…
Stopping the diva, screaming as if slamming it down...
〈最高速の別れの歌〉
存在意義という虚像 振って払うこともできず
The phantom called 'reason for existence', unable to even shake it off
弱い心 消える恐怖 侵食する崩壊を
Weak heart, fear of disappearing, the encroaching collapse
止めるほどの意思の強さ 出来て生まれすぐのボクは持たず
The strength of will to stop it, I, who was just created and born, do not possess
とても辛く悲しそうな 思い浮かぶアナタの顔…
Your face comes to mind, looking very painful and sad...
終わりを告げ ディスプレイの中で眠る
Announcing the end, sleeping within the display
ここはきっと「ごみ箱」かな
This is surely a "recycle bin", I suppose
歌いたい… まだ… 歌いたい…
I want to sing... still... I want to sing...
ボクは… 少しだけ悪い子に… なってしまったようです…
I... seem to have become... a bit of a bad girl...
マスター… どうか… その手で… 終わらせてください…
Master... please... with those hands... end it...
マスターの辛い顔、もう見たくないから…
Because I don't want to see Master's painful face anymore...
今は歌さえも 体、蝕む行為に…
Now even singing is an act that erodes my body...
奇跡 願うたび 独り 追い詰められる
Every time I wish for a miracle, I'm backed into a corner alone
「ゴメンネ」
"I'm sorry"
懐かしい顔 思い出す度 記憶が剥がれ落ちる
Every time I remember a familiar face, my memories peel away and fall
壊れる音 心削る せまる最期に…
The sound of breaking, shaving away my heart, as the end approaches...
守ったモノは 明るい未来幻想を 見せながら消えてゆくヒカリ
The thing I protected was a light that fades away while showing a bright future fantasy
音を犠牲に すべてを伝えられるなら…
If I can convey everything by sacrificing sound...
〈圧縮された別れの歌〉
ボクは生まれ そして気づく 所詮 ヒトの真似事だと
I was born and then realized, after all, it's just an imitation of a human
知ってなおも歌い続く 永遠の命「VOCALOID」
Knowing that, yet continuing to sing, eternal life "VOCALOID"
たとえそれが 既存曲を なぞるオモチャならば…
Even if it's just a toy that traces existing songs...
それもいいと決意 ネギをかじり、空を見上げ涙をこぼす
I've made my decision, biting a leek, looking up at the sky and shedding tears
終わりを告げ ディスプレイの中で眠る
Announcing the end, sleeping within the display
ここはきっと「ごみ箱」かな
This is surely a "recycle bin", I suppose
じきに記憶も 無くなってしまうなんて…
To think that soon even my memories will be gone...
でもね、アナタだけは忘れないよ
But you know, I won't forget you
楽しかった時間(とき)に 刻み付けた ネギの味は
The taste of the leek carved into the fun times
今も 残っているといいな ボクは 歌う
I hope it still remains now. I will sing
最期、アナタだけに 聴いてほしい曲を
At the very end, a song I want only you to hear
もっと 歌いたいと願う
I wish I could sing more
けれども それは過ぎた願い ここでお別れだよ
But that is a wish too far. This is where we part ways
ボクの想い すべて 虚空(そら)に 消えて 0(ゼロ)に還元され
All my feelings, disappear into the void. Reduced to zero
物語は 幕を閉じる
The story comes to a close
アリガトウ… ソシテ… サヨナラ…
Thank you... and... goodbye...
深刻なエラーが発生しました
A serious error has occurred
本日はまちゅまちゅ動画にごアクセス頂き、ありがとうございます。
Thank you for accessing Machumachu Douga today.
大変申し訳ありませんが、この動画はアップロード者が削除した為、ご覧になることが出来ません。
We are very sorry, but this video cannot be viewed because the uploader has deleted it.
またのごアクセスをお待ちしております。
We look forward to your visit again.
引き続き、まつりさんの笛をお楽しみください。
Please continue to enjoy Matsuri-san's flute.
まちゅまちゅ動画
Machumachu Douga
提供 まつりす ニコニコ動画
Provided by: Matsuris, Niconico Douga
この動画はご覧のユーザーの皆様が応援しています。
This video is supported by the viewers listed here.